Muhammad Adam

Process oriented data analyst with 2 years of experience. Experienced in interpreting and analyzing data for a telco and media company. Furnish insights, analytics, and business intelligence needed to guide decisions. Bachelor's degree in Engineering from Al-Azhar Indonesia University.

adammuhammad92@gmail.com

+62 852 2097 0243

Jakarta, Indonesia

linkedin.com/in/muhammad-adam-56a743113

github.com/AdamMuhammad01

WORK EXPERIENCE

Data Analyst

Media Nusantara Citra (MNC)

01/2022 - Present MNC is The largest and most integrated media company in Southeast Asia Jakarta, Indonesia

- Handling data from 4TV(RCTI, MNCTV, GTV, and INews).
- Conduct data analysis using MySQL, Ms-Excel(VBA), and Python (Jupyter) to provide the product and business teams with insights and create business intelligence dashboard using Power BI.
- Interpret data, analyze results using statistical techniques and provide ongoing reports.
- Acquire data from primary or secondary data sources and maintain databases/data systems and Identify, analyze, and interpret trends or patterns in complex data sets.
- Preparing reports and ad-hoc analysis at the request of stakeholders.

Data Analyst

PT. Quadratel Persada

10/2018 - 06/2020 Jakarta, Indonesia Qtel Established and specialist in a wide range of telecommunication product and services with telco technology infrastructure sector.

- Collect data from any sources (sales report) & compared data sales value with revenue expectation(monthly, quarterly, annual).
- Create an evaluation report (monthly) & sales analysis to looking sales trends and manage sales forecast.
- Make a descriptive analysis report with a summary for managerial level purposes.

Project Engineer

PT. ZTE Indonesia

telecommunications industry.

09/2017 - 10/2018

ZTE is a global leader in telecommunications and information technology, end-to-end product lines in the

- Succeeded reach the best performance 100% working target with the team, given by the client in the 2nd quarter of 2018.
- Handling ZTE wireline products, including problem management, problem analysis, monitoring, service operations, and maintenance throughout all regions in Indonesia.
- Responsible for the documents progress report, consisting of product knowledge, Product analysis, configuration audit and optimization, security audit and hardening implementation, and Root Cause Analysis Report (RCA).

EDUCATION

Data Science Program

Purwadhika Startup Coding School

Jakarta, Indonesia

Jakarta, Indonesia

- Final Project: Analyze and Predict The 2016 U.S. Presidential Election using The Linear Regression Method based on Demographics.

B.Eng. in Electrical Engineering

University of Al Azhar Indonesia

SKILLS

Data Visualization

Business intelligence (BI)

Data Analyst

Ms-Excel

MySQL

Python

Tableau & Power BI

ORGANIZATIONS & ACTIVITY

Data Analyst Mentor (08/2022 - Present)

- Mentoring 25 college students from any major.
- assist mentees to perform analyze data using python, SQL, and Tableau.
- Advised mentees to compose stories based on the dataset, including performing Exploratory Data Analyst (EDA) snd the final project (prediction model).

Indonesia Asian Games 2018 Organizing Committee (INASGOC) as Telecommunications Department

Innovation for the Nation Essay Championship Organized by Inovator Nusantara

Semifinalist (2017)

Volunteer at Jakarta International BNI Java Jazz Festival 2016 as IT Division

Microsoft "Global Student Technology Competition" Imagine Cup Indonesia

Members of Committee (2015)

International Seminar on Science and Technology Innovations (ISSTIN) (2015)

LANGUAGES

Bahasa

Native or Bilingual Proficiency

Professional Working Proficiency

INTERESTS

Soccer

Traveling